You're saying that the Fourth
Great Ninja War is about to start?
ミフネ隊長！　先ほど本部から連絡。
Even if it is Madara Uchiha,
敵は我々の足元　地下深くを
通り越しているようです。
can he really take on
the Five Great Nations?
（ミフネ）現場の感知部員が
感知できぬとは。
Wake up!
ただの人間ではないでござるな。
Madara Uchiha leads the Akatsuki.
よし　縦に長く陣形を展開している
拙者たち第五部隊の中で→
Just one of their members, Nagato,
was able to destroy
Hidden Leaf Village!
Have you already forgotten that?!
第二部隊　黄ツチにいちばん近い
いくつかの小隊を→
I agree with Lady Tsunade.
増援に向かわせるでござる。
The Akatsuki already have
the Tailed Beasts
急げ！
from the One Tail to the Seven Tails.
If they intend to use them
as military weapons,
then we must consider their strength
to be far greater than Nagato's.
And if that is the case,
the Five Great Nations…
（サイ）次々　行くよ！　ザジは狼煙を！
（ザジ）オーケー！
no, the entire world is
in danger of ruin.
We cannot delay action any longer.
All right. But do you know
where Uchiha Madara is?
（カカシ）赤い狼煙
奇襲部隊だ　行くぞ！
（ガイ）うん。
We have a general idea
of the location.
（白）大丈夫ですか？　再不斬さん。
The Mitarashi Unit just
reported in and
（再不斬）術の
無駄使いだったようだな　白。
they confirmed spotting someone who
fits the description of Madara Uchiha.
この穢土転生
死人だけに死なねえようだ。
I see.
They are presently working
to get more solid intel.
この術も気にくわねえ。
よく気づいたな　白。
It doesn't rhyme.
確かに　あの大鳥は
つがい２組で飛びます。
Isn't there a nice phrase?
エサを協力して捕るためです。
Unless we are sure about
the enemy's headquarters,
でも　それは
子供を育てる冬の時期だけ。
and where their hideout is,
it will be difficult to launch
an effective surprise attack.
そして　雲に紛れての狼煙。
And so, we will first dispatch
a reconnaissance team.
間違いなく
攻撃してきた相手は　あそこ。
All right.
– To maximize their efforts, we will have
– "All right," eh?
– three surprise attack formations.
–  Lacks originality.
僕に任せてください。
To ensure success,
– each formation must be comprised of
– What if I switch it around like…
– expert shinobi from the Five Great Nations.
– Right-o?
（オモイ）雪？
冷気？
Right-o… And then I add
a little rap flavor and…
Yo right-o.
秘術　魔鏡氷晶！
Yo right-o, yo right-o, yo right-o yo…
うわっ！
This gives us
a pretty clear picture of
the Hidden Cloud's military strength.
うわぁ。
Lucky for us,
the Eight Tails is a fool.
It's not working.
This phrase
is making me mad!
Can't figure it out.
We don't have current intel
about the enemy,
いって～。
so we must rely on intel from
the others to assess the situation.
おい　あれって…。
So we're to go empty-handed and
depend on intel
from other villages?
なんだ　子供ばっかじゃない。
Will they even share their data?
死なない体か
相撃ちでいいってことか。
If they refuse to divulge
what they know,
こ　こいつら
血継限界の忍ばっかだ。
then the Allied Shinobi Force
is meaningless.
We'll just have to trust them.
俺は違うがな。
君たちに
何の恨みもありませんが→
We don't have time to waste.
僕たちの意思では
どうしようもない。
At this every moment,
Madara Uchiha is preparing for war.
来る！
All right!
We will hold a meeting of
the Allied Shinobi Force in three days!
Send word to each village!
カカシさん？
Shortly, I will make
an announcement
（サイ）カカシさん　助かりました！
to everyone in the village about
the impending Fourth Great Ninja War.
安心するのは早いかもしれないよ
こいつらは厄介な忍ばかりだ。
Fourth Great Ninja War…
戦うことになるのはわかってたが
まさか　お前だとはな　カカシ。
You didn't know this yet, Sakura.
But Madara Uchiha
has declared war.
It's not a war between
nations this time.
The Five Great Nations
have joined forces for a war,
the likes of which has
never been seen.
The enemy is…
((雷切！))
None other than the Akatsuki.
The Akatsuki…
We're really going to fight Sasuke.
あの橋の上で
お前らに　とどめをもらって→
When the fighting breaks out,
many will be stricken with anxiety.
俺は地獄に行くばずだった
が　気がつくと→
It will be your job to monitor
their mental state.
白と同じ場所にいた。
ここは　どうやら地獄でも
天国でもないらしい。
Circulate among each team and
report anything that you deem necessary.
Do not hide anything.
ここは現実の世界。
I understand.
お前たちは
穢土転生の術にかかっている。
Also, make sure you keep
an eye on Naruto.
穢土転生？
そうだ。
I cannot have him acting recklessly.
暁が　お前たちを蘇らせた
死の世界からな。
In this war,
the Akatsuki's goal is Naruto.
なんだ　知り合いなのか？
カカシ隊長の合図を待て。
（サクラ）再不斬…　白…。
What's going on, Shizune?
Well, just now…
（再不斬）ほぅ　大きくなったな
カカシの部下の　くの一。
Naruto suddenly disappeared
from Ichiraku.
What?!
You don't suppose the enemy…
あの小僧は　元気にしてるか？
It's impossible for Naruto to
be kidnapped from this village!
え？　うん…。
Find Naruto immediately!
((ナルト：あんた…　誰？
あのさ　あのさ！
この草　とればいいの？
The Five Kage's Decision
（白）うん。
この草が薬草？
すみません
手伝わせちゃって。
See you, Giant Gramps Sage.
姉ちゃん　朝から大変だなぁ。
All right, I'm sending you back.
君こそ　こんなところで
朝から何をやってたんです？
修業！！
I'm back.
俺ってば
もっと強くなりてえんだ！
Where'd you go?
I thought you suddenly disappeared,
and now you're back!
う～ん　でも君は
十分　強そうに見えますよ。
I had something to do.
ダメダメ！　俺ってば　もっともっと
強くなりてえの！
Oh, Naruto!
They said you suddenly disappeared
and everyone's in an uproar.
それは　何のために？
Huh? No kidding!
I never thought I'd run into you here.
俺の里で
一番の忍者になるため！
みんなに　俺の力を
認めさせてやんだよ。
Oh hey!
Give me your autograph!
それに　今は　あることを
あるやつに証明するため！
Could you make it out to my kid.
He's a big fan of yours.
それは　誰かのためですか？
それとも　自分のためにですか？
Autograph?
The hero of the Hidden Leaf.
The kid who created a miracle,
Naruto Uzumaki.
ん？
フフ…。
何がおかしいんだってばよ？
Give me your autograph too!
君には　大切な人がいますか？
What is it? You refuse?
Oh no, but I'm not used
to that sort of thing.
I don't have a clue what to sign.
人は　大切な何かを
守りたいと思ったときに→
Everyone’s making a fuss
over him lately as the miracle kid.
本当に強くなれるものなんです。
But until just recently,
it was just the opposite.
I can’t blame the boy.
Gentlemen, will you let him eat
a bowl of ramen before that?
それは　俺も
よくわかってるってばよ。
Oh, sure…
Yes!
君は　強くなる。
また　どこかで会いましょう。
I finally get to eat!
Naruto!
(うん！))
Oh Sakura!
（再不斬）俺たちを
負かしやがったんだ。
Where have you been?!
今ごろは　でかくなってんだろう。
Where? I was suddenly
summoned and…
名前もな。
（カカシ）あぁ。
Just come with me right now!
Lady Tsunade and everyone else
are worried about you!
あの橋は
ナルト大橋って名がついたし→
Oww… Sakura!
Let me eat my ramen!
今じゃ　里のみんなに　英雄
奇跡の少年なんて呼ばれてるよ。
That can wait.
With the Great Lord Elder?
お前たちのおかげで　ナルトは
己の忍道を見つけることができた。
Yeah, he used
a Reverse Summoning Jutsu.
Jeez, after all the trouble…
そして　それを
お前らの墓の前で誓ったんだ。
Lord Fukasaku could at least
notify me first.
あのときから
ブレない立派な忍に成長した。
Still, it's a relief that
you're okay, Naruto.
なら　彼はもっと強くなる。
Yup, I'm alive and well.
（カブト）少しは　昔話ができたかな？
But why did the Great Lord Elder
summon you?
そろそろ本気でいくよ。
Giant Gramps Sage had
a prophecy for me too.
力が　みなぎってくる。
ここからが本番だ！
カカシ…　俺たちを　止め…。
Like the one he foretold to Jiraiya?
What did the Great Lord Elder say?
Well…
What's the matter?
引け！
I'm gonna go to some resort
and encounter an octopus.
カカシさん　この人たち…。
Huh? An octopus?
あぁ　間違いない。
鬼人　桃地再不斬！
そして　氷遁の白！
What is that supposed to mean?
Well, this octopus is gonna cooperate
with me somehow.
((カカシ先生！！
君の相手は　僕です！
Giant Gramps Sage didn't know
the details either.
白！
悪いが
一瞬で終わらせてもらうぞ。
And…
he said that I'm going to
end up fighting Sasuke.
（再不斬）写輪眼か。
そんなものは　俺には効かねえ！
Sasuke?
忍法　霧隠れの術！
But I'm already prepared for that.
（再不斬）もらったぁ！
これが　音だけで相手を倒す
サイレントキリング！
Naruto…
Sakura, it's all right.
Just let me deal with Sasuke.
なぜだ？
霧隠れの鬼人と呼ばれたお前が→
ただの傭兵に　なり下がるのは？
再不斬！
戯言を言うな！
It's quiet.
忍の世界には　利用する人間と→
I know.
利用される人間の
どちらかしかない！
So peaceful.
しょせん　忍は　ただの道具よ。
Huh? No, it's not.
俺たち忍者に
理想など　必要ない！
Well sure, the village that
Pain destroyed is being rebuilt,
弱い忍者は　僕たちの世界に
必要としないんです。
and Lady Tsunade has
come out of her coma.
But as for Sasuke,
there's only talk that Naruto
will do something.
どうして　お前は
あんなやつのために！？
僕は　大切な人を守りたい…。
And there's gonna be a war, right?
大切な人の夢を　叶えたいんです。
How did you know that?
ナルト君…。
I'm not stupid.
I can tell by watching the jonin.
君に　必要とされない悲しみが
わかりますか？
I guess so.
再不斬さんは　僕を
必要としてくれているんです。
The fact is war is right
at our doorstep.
僕が　物心ついた頃…。
僕の父は
僕を殺そうとしたんです…。
I see… I figured as much.
僕の国では
血継限界を持つ人間は→
Yeah. This is fight is going
to be something we…
忌み嫌われてきました。
I mean, no shinobi
has ever experienced.
そして　そのとき僕は→
自分のことを　こう思った…。
I mean, the Five Great Nations
are joining forces for the first time
自分が　この世に
まるで必要とされない存在だと。
to crush the Akatsuki.
《俺と同じ…》
It's the start of
the Fourth Great Ninja War.
再不斬さんは
そんな僕を拾ってくれた。
The Fourth Great Ninja War.
僕を好んで　必要としてくれた。
Aren't you scared, Shikamaru?
嬉しかった…。
Sure, I'm scared.
But this time,
僕は　再不斬さんの武器です…。
it doesn't matter how scared
we are or how hard it'll be.
言いつけを守る　ただの道具として
おそばに　置いてください。
Our enemy, the Akatsuki,
is made up of members so skilled
that it took just one of them, Pain,
to destroy Hidden Leaf Village.
けど　納得いかねえ！
(強いことだけが　この世にいていい
っていう理由なのかよ！))
And the abilities of their leader,
Madara, are shrouded in mystery.
Madara already has seven
Tailed Beasts in his possession.
くっ…　意識が遠のいていく…。
If he unleashes
all of them at once,
クソ…　が…。
who knows if
the Five Great Nations can win.
頭の中が…　熱い…。
The very existence of
the ninja world is at stake.
くっ…。
鬼のオーラ…
こいつが鬼人　再不斬か！
Each and every shinobi
will have to do his best
その上　氷遁の子！
in order for us to win.
Choji, I'm counting on
your strength!
構えろ！　気を抜くなよ　ガイ！
Shikamaru… I wonder if
I can do my best?
サイレントキリングで
こいつの右に出る者はいない。
カカシさん…　お願いします…。
Still, it's hard to take
this all in, huh?
もう一度　僕たちを…
止めてください。
僕の夢は
再不斬さんの道具として…。
再不斬さんを守り抜き
死ぬことだった…。
Are you okay?
You wanted to know what
to expect from war.
こうして…。
I'm fine.
再不斬さんも　この術に
かけられているということは→
But nothing can prepare you
for the real battlefield.
あのとき　僕があなたから…。
The cries of the wounded,
the smell of blood…
再不斬さんを
守りきれなかったということ…。
It's impossible not to
be affected by that.
そしてまた…
再不斬さんを守るどころか→
And yet, a Medical Ninja must
maintain composure at all times.
今は…　再不斬さんの
道具にもなれない…。
Everyone fights hard,
いや…
君は　再不斬を守ったんだ。
believing that we will be
there to save their lives.
いや…
君は　再不斬を守ったんだ。
I understand.
That's why I wanted to…
彼が死んだのは
もっと　別の理由…　そして。
to know.
再不斬は　君のことを道具だなんて
思っちゃいなかった。
Well, I've rambled on enough.
カ…　カシ…
よけいなことを　ベラベラと…。
Damn it. A poor talker like me
lecturing you, it’s not my style.
ナルトが…　再不斬の心の奥を
浮き彫りにしたのさ。
((けっ…　偉そうな口利いて
このザマかよ。
If we both end up dying…
弱えくせによ！
You won’t be an Uchiha and
I won’t be the Nine Tails' Jinchuriki.
白！　てめえ！
We'll be free of all our burdens.
And we'll finally be able to understand
each other in the next world.
ぐっ…。
迂闊に動くな！
ナルト　敵の数を考えろ！
Naruto…you…
だって…　だってよぉ！
やめろ　小僧。
やつの言うとおりだ。
If both Naruto and Sasuke
are seriously wounded…
白は　弱いから死んだ…。
which one will I save first?
なに言ってんだってばよ！
あいつは…。
あんたのために死んだんだぞ！
ガトーが　俺を利用したように…。
Found you!
俺も　白を
利用していただけのことだ…。
Be quiet!
（再不斬）言ったはずだ。
忍の世界には　利用する人間と→
Master, what's the meaning of this?
利用される人間の
どちらかしかない。
Don't scare us like that.
俺たち忍は　ただの道具だ。
I'm Killer - Bee - Quiet!
俺がほしかったのは
あいつの血で→
That has a nice cadence.
– And…
– What is it?
あいつ自身じゃない。
ENKA CONCERT
お前ってば…
本気でそう言ってんのか！
These are for us?
To sell?!
やめろ　ナルト！
あいつは…。
I had interference from Brother
in that last recital.
あいつは　お前のことが
ほんとに好きだったんだぞ！
君には　大切な人がいますか？
This time, I'm gonna nail it.
A recital?
あんなに大好きだったんだぞ！
Who's gonna wanna buy these?
人は　大切な
何かを守りたいと思ったときに→
Are you that against hearing me sing?
You fools! You idiots!
本当に強くなれるものなんです。
No, it's not that…
それなのに
ほんとに何とも思わねえのかよ！
Okay, Master! I'll sell tickets
even if it kills me!
ほんとに　ほんとにお前は
何とも思わねえのかよ！
I'm counting on you!
その人の夢を叶えたい。
そのためなら→
You all came quickly.
The situation calls for quick action.
僕は　忍になりきる。
お前みたいに強くなったら→
Princess Tsunade.
Are you really all right?
ほんとに
そうなっちまうのかよ？
This is the perfect opportunity
to hand things over to a youngster.
あいつは　お前のために
命を捨てたんだぞ！
You're old too.
自分の夢　見れねえで
道具として死ぬなんて…。
Speak for yourself,
you Fence-Sitter geezer!
Setting aside the matter of Danzo,
そんなの辛すぎるってばよ…。
I'm relieved that you are back
as the Hokage, Lady Tsunade.
（再不斬）小僧…。
Let us be done with the greetings
and get right to business.
それ以上　何も言うな。
First on the agenda are
the Jinchuriki of the
Eight Tails and Nine Tails.
白は　お前らのためにも
心を痛めながら戦っていた。
Then we will go on to any intel
relating to the enemy's headquarters
and military strength.
俺にはわかる。
あいつは　優しすぎた。
My shinobi have pinned
down a location
that may be the enemy’s stronghold.
最期にお前らと
やれてよかった。
But it may be a trap.
なあ小僧　結局は
お前の言うとおりだった。
We have no choice but to wait
for more intel on this.
I also have a reconnaissance team
gathering intel.
忍も人間だ。　感情のない道具には
なれないのかもな…。
We need to sort through the intel
from each village quickly.
俺の負けだ。
How about forming a separate unit
within the Allied Force
再不斬…。
that only handles intel?
お前たちは手を出すな！
Good idea!
Share and share alike!
これは　俺の戦いだ！
That goes without saying!
うお～っ！！
If each nation becomes driven
by self-interest,
the Akatsuki will pull the rug out
from under us.
So, where will we hide
the crucial Jinchuriki?
Hide them?
雪…　こんな時期に。
What is it?
Naruto and Bee can lend much
strength to this battle.
Why hide them away?
白よ…　泣いているのか…。
I thought so as well.
But those two are what the enemy
is after in this war.
ずっとそばにいたんだ。
Considering what could happen,
we cannot let them participate.
せめて最期もお前のそばで…。
It was decided at the last meeting,
but you, of course,
were still ill.
Our enemy is Madara!
If we hold back battle strength and
lose the prospect of victory,
できるなら　死んでも
お前と一緒にいてえな　俺も…。
we are not going to get another chance.
We must hit them with
everything we've got…
The Five Great Nations
joined together and
our aim in this war is
to protect those two.
Your sole dissent as Hokage
is not sufficient.
We will decide this
with majority rule.
(いられるさ　再不斬…。
２人一緒に))
You child! Naruto is—
I know him quite well.
Putting us through
all this trouble!
再不斬と白か　意外としつこいね。
まだ　縛りきれないとは。
If it's for a friend,
he gets too reckless.
That is exactly why.
ククク…　今にただの
殺りく人形にしてあげるよ。
Before we even talk
about military strength,
君らは　僕の道具だ。
the five Kage must reach a consensus.
Otherwise, there will be no victory.
カ…　カシ。　容赦するな。
I agree, Lady Tsunade.
俺をどんな手を
使っても止めろ。
It's fine!
The Slug Princess is back
to her impudent self.
俺はもう死んだ。
It's proof that she is well.
人間として死んだんだ。
We will now need to decide
where to hide
the Eight Tails and Nine Tails.
Any objections, Hokage?
あぁ…　わかってるよ。
I understand.
Get on with it!
I have a place in mind.
再不斬さん　ありがとう…。
And it is appropriately located
in the Hidden Cloud,
which has not produced
any Akatsuki members.
I set it aside, just in case.
くるぞ！
カカシ隊長　あの岩隠れの男ですが→
Why do you need to speak
in private?
血継限界　爆遁の使い手。
I need a favor.
デイダラと同じ　元爆破部隊のガリ！
A favor?
I understand that
your younger brother, Bee,
そして　あの人は砂隠れ
血継限界　灼遁の使い手　パクラです。
has the Eight Tails completely
under control.
I want Bee to teach Naruto.
気をつけてください。
血継限界ばかりか…。
About how to control the Nine Tails.
忍法　霧隠れの術。
How convenient for you.
感知忍者を中心に戦闘隊を組め！
If that brat named Naruto learns
他は　１２　３　６
９時の方向をカバーしつつ→
to completely manipulate
the Nine Tails
he will be the ultimate weapon
for the Hidden Leaf.
卍の陣を基本としろ！
再不斬は　音だけで
ターゲットの位置をつかむ！
And you want me to readily
agree to that?
（ガイ）霧が濃くなっていく…。
視界が悪すぎる。
I know all that.
But this is not the time to be arguing
about our own interests!
（リー）サクラさん
怖がらなくても大丈夫です。
僕が　死んでも守りぬきますから！
We are up against Madara Uchiha!
前回は　この陣の死角である
中央から攻撃してきたの。
The time will come when
we will have no choice
but to use Bee and Naruto's powers!
背中にも気をつけて。
任せてください！
It will be too late if we wait until then!
え…？　あ　はい！
Don't shout so much.
Is that any way to make a request?
霧の次は…　冷気。
ぐわっ！
I’m sorry.
You have a point though.
始まった！
やはり　前回までとは違う。
And, I considered that ages ago.
ここまで強く縛りきれるとは…
さすが　大蛇丸様のチャクラだ…。
What?! What are you saying?
The place I'm sending those two
isn't just a hideout.
僕用のコントロール札を
上書きできるとはね…。
I said I set it aside, didn’t I?
しかし　敵を精神的に
追い込むつもりで→
Long ago, Bee and I trained
on that island.
感情をわざと残したが…。
それだとやはり
縛りが弱い分→
S-rank mission?!
心の変化で
魂が昇天してしまった。
You're assigning me to
an important mission like that?
今度は　感情を殺して縛りきる。
Yes. This is a mission that
only you can undertake.
今のところそれができる
コマの数はわからないが…。
You and Yamato will go
to a certain place
in the Hidden Cloud region.
まあ　データを
この戦争で取っていくか…。
《残りのコマは　今までどおり
命令を守る縛りくらいで→
Is that the resort?
The Great Lord Elder's prophecy
was accurate.
あとは　勝手にさせておこう。
感情を残しておいたほうが→
It seems that is the place
he foresaw.
有利になるやつらも
いるだろうしね…》
Then I'm gonna see the octopus
at this resort island?
I feel sorta bad!
Everyone's so busy and
I get to go to a resort.
ミイラ化してる…　この術は…。
You fool! You are going
on a mission!
くるぞ！
I know. Just joking, just joking.
But about going to this place
that was prophesied…
灼遁　過蒸殺！
体の中が…。
Is it connected to the other one?
That I'll fight with Sasuke?
爆遁　地雷拳！
That, I don't know.
However, we are on the verge of war!
そんな…　タジキが爆発した…。
Hence, this S-rank mission.
うお～っ！　この野郎が！
When you get to the site,
you will follow Yamato's orders.
（２人）木ノ葉つむじ旋風！
Okay! I understand!
You can count on me
for this S-rank mission!
ガイさん！
Dress casually for enka.
戦場では　仲間が死ぬ。
それは最低でも覚悟して来い！
Yup, I look pretty good.
Where is Bee?!
とり乱すと
余計　仲間が死ぬことになる！
W-What's up, Brother?!
仲間の死を次に活かせ！
わかったか新人！
You surprised me too much.
You're going on a mission.
Leave immediately!
は　はい！
What's with that get-up?!
頑張って　大丈夫よ。
敵の連係と
手の内がわかってきた。
Let's go!
The concert is in three days.
今度は　こっちからだ！
ククク…　相手のペースを
作らせるほど僕は甘くないよ。
PASSION ON FIRE
LIVE ENKA CONCERT
（２人）口寄せの術！
♪～
まさか　ここまで…。
こ　これは…。
（カカシ）霧隠れ忍刀七人衆の
前任者たちだ！
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華歌手
１０組の皆さんによる→